Hello.
In this lecture, I want to go over how to add future controls to the game.
I recorded this course in action.
5.0.
Since then, Unreal Engine 5.1 has released, which made a major update to how unreal Engine handles
controls in future videos.
On this course.
When I set up systems like dashing and attacking, I'll use the old way of adding controls.
It still works, although the system is deprecated.
So in this video I want to show you how to set up new controls in the new version of Unreal Engine,
and you can use this video as a reference on how to add new controls to the game.
So let's say we want to add a new control for whenever the player character is dashing.
What we do is go over to the input folder, go over to actions, and then right click and go input,
select input action.
Then call this I a whatever you want the new control to be.
So I want to set up a new control for dashing.
So I'll call this a dash.
Then if I go over to the input folder and go over to IMC default and I'm going to go create new mapping.
I'll select the dash and then let's say I want to make it so that whenever the player presses the Z
one dash, so I look for Z, I can then go save close this.
And if I go back to my player character blueprint in order to code the dashing y, I do it just right
click and go dash and we want to select enhance action event I dash.
And then what you do is we'd have the code for how to set up the dashing you'd want to connect from
started into whatever the code for the dashing is you don't want to use triggered because triggered
basically runs as long as the player character is holding down the key.
We only use started for using one of events.
So if say for example, the player character presses the Z onto dash, you want to hook this up to start
it that way.
It only occurs once.
If it's on trigger, then it will continuously occur as long as that key is held down.
So use the started when adding one off event and for the rest of the course.
When we set up new controls, we only use one of events.
So you can just hook this up to start it.